radiojar.com 2019-11-04

# Radiojar Privacy policy

Radiojar is committed to protecting the personal data and privacy of visitors Radiojar website (the "website") and users of the Radiojar service the ‘service’). For this reason, this Privacy Policy has been developed ("Policy") that describes and explains what kind of personal data collected by Radiojar and how Radiojar manages and processes them. By visiting the website and using it, you accept this Policy, you explicitly agree to the collection, use and processing of your Personal Data (as defined below) in accordance with this Policy. You also consent to the collection, retention and use of cookies by Radiojar, as described in our cookie policy. 

## Information regarding this Privacy Policy

This Policy applies to the information we collect from you and process when navigating in Radiojar website and when using the Service. Unless otherwise specified in this Policy, the terms used in this Policy have the same meaning as the Terms of Use. 

In the future, Radiojar website may provide additional uses and gain increased functionality. If this entails any change in the way your personal data is collected and processed, you will be provided with more details and additional terms in this Policy. Unless otherwise stated, any new use / service of the site being imported will be subject to this Policy. 

In the event that the use of any service on this website is governed by a specific privacy policy, this particular policy will apply in conjunction with this Policy. In the event of a conflict or contradiction between the terms of this Policy and the terms of a more specific policy, the terms of the particular privacy policy of each service will prevail. 

The purpose of this Policy is: 

  1. Ensure that you know what personal data we collect about you, the reasons why we collect and process it, and with whom we share it. 
  2. Explain how we use the personal data you have shared with us.
  3. Explain your rights in relation to your personal data you have shared with us

## Definitions

**“Personal data”** means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (‘data subject’); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person. Personal data, as used in this Policy, also includes information about an individual's activities, such as information about his or her activity on our Service, and demographic information, such as date of birth, gender, geographic area, and preferences, when any of this information is linked directly to personal information that identifies that individual. 

**“Processing”** means any operation or set of operations which is performed on personal data or on sets of personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organisation, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction. 

**“Applicable data protection and privacy legislation”** means General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (EU) and European legislation regarding protection of privacy in the communications sector, as implemented in Greek legal order. 

## Legal bases for the collection of information

We collect and process information lawfully: 

  1. for the performance of the contract between RadioJar and registered users of our Service.
  2. For the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by Radiojar
  3. Based on the users’ consent provided to receive newsletters/promotional material and to analyse its consuming behavior/ for statistical purposes. 
  4. In order to comply with legal obligations to which we are subject

## The Information We Collect:

Certain personal data is provided directly by registered users (e.g. registration data), while some personal data are collected indirectly when visitors of the site navigate through it ("visitors"). 

  1. ### Visitors of the website

When you navigate our website, our web server temporarily stores by default personal data for the purpose of system security, namely: 

    1. the connection data of the inquiring computer (IP address)
    2. the pages you visit on our website, the date and duration of the visit
    3. the identification data of the employed browser and operating system type
    4. the website from which you accessed our website

The above personal data of visitors to the site are limited to the information required for the operation and improvement of this website and of our services and for the purpose of system security in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy law. We store such data for a limited time-period, which does not exceed 6 months from the date of collection. After 6 months from the collection date all such data are permanently deleted from our systems. However, we may store and process above-mentioned collected data in their form as completely anonymized, statistical data, only for usage metrics and statistical purposes. 

  2. ### Users of the services who need to register and create their own user account

When a user signs-up for the Service, we ask for the following information which the user of our service voluntarily provides: 

    1. First/last name
    2. Country
    3. Region
    4. City
    5. Street address
    6. Postal code
    7. Telephone number
    8. Email
    9. Password

Users can **optionally** provide: 

    1. Birthday
    2. Gender
    3. Timezone
    4. Nickname
    5. Profile pic
    6. Bio
    7. Tags
    8. Facebook profile
    9. Twitter profile

We use the information you provide or that we collect to operate, maintain, enhance, and provide all of the features and services found on the Service, and for any other purposes that we may disclose to you at the point at which we request your personal information and your consent. We will use your email address or other contact information to contact you for administrative purposes, for customer service purposes, to address intellectual property infringement, rights of privacy, or defamation issues, or any questions or issues regarding use of Radiojar Service or other content you may publish to, or transmit using, the Service. 

Regarding the location information that you may provide or that we collect, we will use it to provide content and services to you that we believe may be relevant to you based in whole or in part on your location. 

Moreover, we may use information that you provide to us or that we collect through the Service, including personal information, to tailor and provide advertising and other content, to you more effectively. 

In addition, we use the information that you provide or that we collect and/or aggregate, including personal information, to understand and analyze the usage trends, interests, and preferences of our users, to improve the way the Service works and looks, and to create new features, functionality, products, and services. 

Finally, we may use "automatically collected" information to: (a) personalize the Service, such as remembering your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Service; (b) monitor and analyze the effectiveness of the Service and marketing activities on the Service (including by third parties); (c) monitor aggregate usage metrics such as total number of users (d) track your entries, submissions, and status in any promotions or other activities that may be offered on the Service from time to time. 

  3. ### Visitors of the website who subscribe to our newsletter

Our website visitors who want to receive Radiojar’s internet radio newsletter provide us their email address which we only use for the particular purpose and we never share with anyone else. Users who do not want to receive our newsletter anymore can unsubscribe at any time. 

  4. ### Users of third-party connected services

Visitors of our website and users of our services with accounts on certain third-party services, namely Facebook, Twitter, Google+, can either (a) connect to our Service through such third-party services or (b) log in to such third-party services through our website. Third-party services may be provided by more third-party services provides in the future. 

In case you connect to our Service through a third-party connected service you may be able to send alerts, comments, tweets and messages on such third-party services and may publish some of your activities on our service to the third-party service. 

In any request for authorization to connect to our Service through such third-party services, we may ask you for additional rights or permission with respect to third-party connected services and information, including personal information that we obtain from them. 

In particular, if you permit us to connect to your Facebook profile, either during log-in or by electing to use the third-party connected services links available, we may collect information from your Facebook profile such as your name, email, gender, birthday, current city, profile picture URL, list of friends. We do not share this information with anyone and we only use to automatically fill in your registration details according to Section 4 (b) above. 

Also, if you sign in to Twitter via our website, we collect all information, including personal information, that may be available to us through the Twitter API relating to your Twitter account, including, but not limited to, your Twitter account's photo, name, last mentions, your followers, and your followers who follow you back. We do not share this information with anyone and we only use to automatically fill in your registration details according to Section 4 (b) above. 

Finally, if you sign in to Google+ via our website, we collect the following information: name and e-mail. We do not share this information with anyone and we only use to automatically fill in your registration details according to Section 4 (b) above. 

By connecting to any Third-Party Connected Services in connection with our Service, you permit us to access and use all information related to your account on the Third-Party Connected Service that may be accessible to us pursuant to this Policy. To limit or control the information that is available to us through any such Third-Party Connected Service, or to disconnect any Third-Party Connected Service from our Service, you should check (and, if applicable, modify) the applicable settings on the Third-Party Connected Service. 

Please be aware that any personal information you provide on or to any Third-Party Connected Service by connecting to any Third-Party Connected Services in connection with our Service, is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's Privacy policies. Radiojar does not control and is not responsible for the privacy policies of such Third-Party Connected Services. When using such Third-Party Connected Services, this Policy does not apply and we strongly encourage you to read the relevant privacy policies in order to be informed about the collection and processing of your personal data from the above Third-Party Connected Services. 

  5. ### Other functionalities of the Website to share personal information with us

We also provide you with several opportunities to voluntarily provide personal information to us on the Service, that is: (a) through feedback forms, (b) customer support forms. 

In case of (a) feedback forms, you are requested to provide us the following personal information: Name, Email, Company, Inquiry subject and inquiry description. We do not share this information with anyone else and we only use it to assess your feedback and/or get back to you regarding your feedback. 

In case of (b) customer support forms, you are requested to provide us the following personal information: email & company, while you should also put a subject and a short text describing your enquiry. We do not share this information with anyone else and we only use it to reply to your customer support request. Since this service is addressed to registered users having an account, this information is retained until the user requests the deletion of his account. 

  6. ### Payments information

Registered users who have to pay for the Services are transferred to the safe environment of the payment services providers, where it registers the data requested. Radiojar does not store any type of payment data (card items, credit card security codes, etc.) in any way. All transactions made through Radiojar are taking place using an SSL certificate and are therefore encrypted, providing the maximum security against the interception of personal data. 

  7. ### Not collected/stored

Radiojar does not request, knowingly collect and / or process sensitive / special categories personal data. 

Radiojar is committed to protecting the privacy needs of children and does not request, knowingly collect and / or process information from children under the age of 16 and does not target its websites to children under 16. 

## Recipients of your data and data transfers to third countries

The recipients of the Service User data are Radiojar and its employees that may process your personal data strictly under the same terms and conditions as set out in this Policy. Your registration details are kept secure and are not disclosed to third parties for any reason whatsoever. 

Radiojar may use third-party service providers to provide maintenance services, data analysis, service hosting, and other services for us and also other service providers (eg e-mail services) to communicate with you on cases where it has received your explicit consent for this communication. Radiojar only uses third-party service providers who agree to use only the personal information provided to them for the purpose for which it was provided and who agree and guarantee that all processing effected by them will be legal and compliant with the provisions of the applicable personal data and privacy legislation. 

We use third-party analytics services to help understand your usage of our services. In particular, we provide a limited amount of your information (such as sign-up date and some personal information like your email address) to Intercom, Inc. (“Intercom”) and utilize Intercom to collect data for analytics purposes when you visit our website or use our product. As a data processor acting on our behalf, Intercom analyzes your use of our website and/or product and tracks our relationship by way of cookies and similar technologies so that we can improve our service to you. For more information on Intercom's use of cookies, please visit https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#cookie-policy. We may also use Intercom as a medium for communications, either through email, or through messages within our product(s). As part of our service agreements, Intercom collects publicly available contact and social information related to you, such as your email address, gender, company, job title, photos, website URLs, social network handles and physical addresses, to enhance your user experience. For more information on the privacy practices of Intercom, please visit https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy. Intercom’s services are governed by Intercom’s terms of use which can be found at https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#terms. If you would like to opt out of having this information collected by or submitted to Intercom, please contact us. 

Radiojar does not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless you have explicitly given your consent or required by law to disclose such information. In particular, Radiojar may disclose your personal data to third parties when such disclosure is necessary for the assertion, exercise or defense of legal claims either in court proceedings or in the context of a relevant request of Competent Authorities, either in administrative or extrajudicial proceedings, or for the purpose of preventing or interrupting an attack on computer systems or its networks or protecting its rights or property from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses or activity. 

Radiojar uses reliable servers and data centers located within the European Union and are therefore subject to compliance with the provisions of the applicable personal data legislation and also cloud hosting providers who are located in the US and are certified under the US – EU Privacy Shield [(https://www.privacyshield.gov/list)](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). 

Finally, we make certain automatically collected and other aggregate non-personally-identifiable information available to third parties, to: (i) comply with various reporting obligations; (ii) for business or marketing purposes; or (iii) to assist such parties in understanding our users' interests, habits, and usage patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality available through the Service. For example, we may inform our advertisers and other third parties that a certain proportion of the Service's users are female and have used the service to transmit a specific kind of music or other radio transmissions. 

This website may contain links that refer to third-party websites. Radiojar does not control and is not responsible for the privacy policy and privacy practices of such sites. When using these links and moving to these sites, this Policy does not apply and we strongly encourage you to read the relevant privacy policies in order to be informed about the collection and processing of your personal data from the above sites. 

## Data retention

The storage and processing of the data of website’s visitors and users’ of services is done solely as permitted by law or under your explicit consent only for as long as required to meet the purposes of the processing (as defined above) or until you disagree with the use of your personal data by Radiojar or until you withdraw your consent. 

In particular, the personal information of the visitors of the website will be retained and processed according to Section 4 (a) above. 

Registered users’ data will be retained and processed until the registered user requests the deletion of his account or, for any processing of his or her data, on the basis of his consent, until he declares his / her withdrawal of consent for the purposes of providing the Services. Nevertheless, some necessary personal data regarding the user’s contractual relations with Radiojar as well as regarding the information, consent and withdrawal of his consent to the processing of his data will remain as information for the registered user to ensure the proof of the legitimacy of the processing of his data by Radiojar and safeguarding the parties' legal claims. 

Finally, data submitted to Radiojar via feedback and customer support forms will be retained and processed until the provision of the particular service is completed and, as far as feedback is concerned, for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which feedback is requested (i.e. improve the Service, etc). 

## Your rights in relation to your personal data

Upon request, you will be provided with information about whether and how personal data is collected and processed in relation to you ("access right"). If your personal data is incorrect, you have the right: 

  * Ask for their correction to the extent that it is inaccurate and / or incomplete ('right of rectification'). 
  * Ask for their deletion ("Deletion right"). Radiojar will delete your personal data without undue delay under the terms and conditions of the applicable law. Radiojar can only delete the data if there is no legal obligation or if it has no other legal right to maintain it. Certainly if the data of a visitor / user of the site is deleted, then Radiojar is unable to continue providing its services to that user when they require the use of that data. 
  * Ask for the restriction of the processing of your personal data under the terms and conditions of the applicable law and be informed before the restriction of processing is lifted. 
  * Communicate any rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing to each recipient to whom the personal data have been disclosed, unless this proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort, and to be informed of those recipients. 
  * Receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, ie in electronic form, as well as the right to transmit it to another controller ("portability rights"). 
  * At any time, oppose the processing of your personal data based on reasons related to your particular situation ("right to object"). 
  * Do not make a decision that is based solely on an automated decision-making process, such as profiling, since the decision would have legal effects for you or other equally important implications. 
  * Revoke your consent to use your personal data in the future, in whole or in part. The withdrawal of your consent does not affect the legitimacy of the processing based on consent prior to its revocation. 

Finally, under the applicable personal data legislation, you have the right to file a complaint with the Personal Data Protection Authority. 

You may, of course, decline to share certain personal information with us, in which case we would be unable to provide you many of the features and functionality found on the Service. You may update, correct, or delete your profile information and preferences at any time by accessing the "my account" tab through the Service. If you wish to access or amend any other personal information we hold about you, you may contact us at [contact@radiojar.com](mailto:contact@radiojar.com). 

Please be aware that while your changes may be reflected promptly in active user databases, we may retain all information you submit for backup and archiving purposes in case it proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort to remove such information. 

To protect your privacy and security, we may ask you to verify your identity before granting you account access or making corrections to your information. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times. 

## Data Security:

For Radiojar, protecting the privacy of visitors and users of the site and respecting the privacy of the person on the internet is a self-evident commitment. All necessary organizational and technical measures are required to ensure the security, availability and validity of the personal data of visitors and users of the site and to protect them against accidental or unlawful destruction, disclosure and other forms of fraudulent processing. 

Ensure that your personal information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, appropriate physical, electronic and organizational procedures have been put in place to protect and safeguard personal data collected. 

The site uses the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol and therefore provides maximum security against the interception of personal data. This protocol is the standard for the certification of websites for network users and for the encryption of data trafficked between web users and web servers. In addition, SSL ensures that it will be ascertained if the data being trafficked through it has been altered during transport. 

Although we use commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards in an effort to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information, we cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. In case of security breach, we become aware of, we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps and/or post a notice through the Service. We advise you to carefully check all the relevant communications you receive from us. 

## Changes and Updates to this Policy:

We reserve the right to update this Policy at any time without prior notice from time to time by posting a new version on the site. We will process the data in accordance with the Policy in force at the time you provided your consent to the processing of your personal data in accordance with this Policy. When a material change occurs in the Policy, we will notify you accordingly, e.g. via a visible banner on the site, sending a message to your email address, or messaging you through the Service. Material changes to this Policy will be effective upon the earlier of (i) your first use of the Service with actual knowledge of such change, or (ii) 30 days from providing you notice of such change. We encourage you to periodically review this Policy to stay informed about how we collect, use, and disclose information. You should check this page occasionally to make sure you are satisfied with any changes to this Policy and carefully read any relevant notice you receive. By continuing using the site, you consent to the updated Policy. Use the "Last Updated" date in this Policy to learn about when it was last modified. 

### Radiojar Contact Information:

Please send these requests or other questions and comments about this Privacy Policy via e-mail at: [contact@radiojar.com](mailto:contact@radiojar.com) and/or [dpo@radiojar.com](mailto:dpo@radiojar.com). 

Radiojar is committed to protecting your privacy. You can at all times exercise your rights under Section 7 of this Privacy policy via e-mail at [dpo@radiojar.com](mailto:dpo@radiojar.com). Please contact us with any questions or comments about this Policy, your personal information, our third-party disclosure practices, or your consent choices via email at: [contact@radiojar.com](mailto:contact@radiojar.com) and/or [dpo@radiojar.com](mailto:dpo@radiojar.com).
